Keith Billings

4728 N 15th St. Apt 30, Phoenix, AZ 85014 | 11040 SW Greenburg Rd. Apt 309, Portland, OR 97223 (503) 709-9897 | keithbillingsbusiness@gmail.com

Portfolio: www.KeithBillings.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/keithbillings/ | Github: github.com/KeithBillings

Summary

Front end web developer with a passion for React. Brings a variety of skills from different backgrounds into a complete package. Have experience with a startup, always learning and pushing myself, and hungry for more. Graduated University of Oregon's coding bootcamp with the MERN stack, and continues to learn through Udemy courses and work experience. Hungry for more.

Skills

React, Next.js, Javascript, Typescript, Node.js, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Git, Bootstrap, jQuery, MySQL, Sequelize, Express, Docker, communication, teamwork, leadership, organization, time management, and precision

Experience

Jan 2021 - Present

KyFlex, Remote - Front End Web Developer

Contributing to an up and coming startup about sharing experiences and connecting the world. Primarily doing front end web development using React, Javascript, Docker, connecting APIs, Google Authentication, Facebook Authentication, and more!

Jan 2021 - Present

Freelance Web Developer/Web Designer, Remote - Web Developer/Web Designer

Building personal websites, portfolios, online stores. Using React for front end, MongoDB, Express, server hosting services on Heroku, also designing Shopify stores, designing Squarespace stores, and consulting.

January 2018 - March 2020

Hotel deLuxe, Portland, OR - *Maintenance Engineer*

Received accolades that resulted in multiple pay grade increases, successfully completed building an outdoor restaurant area from the ground up, and worked directly with management to address budget issues. Day to Day Duties: HVAC servicing, low voltage electrical, CAT-5 cable laying, plumbing repairs, appliance repairs, woodworking and construction, guest satisfaction, key making, groundskeeping, beekeeping, and special projects

Education

October 2020 - Present

Udemy - Multiple Courses

Course List: Complete React Developer in 2021, Understanding Typescript-2021 edition, The Complete Shopify Masterclass Learning deeper React, Typescript, GraphQL, Firebase, Shopify, and more!

April 2020 - October 2020

University of Oregon - Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Received top of the line training in Javascript, React, Node.js, MySQL, and career development Certificate of Completion from University of Oregon's Coding Bootcamp

December 2018 - February 2019

PCC Swan Island Trade Center - Refrigeration and Electrical

Training classes on HVAC operations, low voltage electrical, transformers, brazing, and refrigerants

September 2010 - June 2012

PCC Cascade Campus - Fire Academy and Fire Protection Services

Received Certifications - Fire Protection 1 and 2

Projects

adVOTEcate - adVOTEcate is a complete full stack web application with a goal of getting users to check to see if they are registered to vote, register to vote if they are not, provide information about voting deadlines, how to vote, and map out where drop box locations are using Google Maps Api. This app uses the MERN stack and a host of other technologies.

Deployment: https://advotecate.herokuapp.com/

Github Repository: https://github.com/KeithBillings/adVOTEcate

Party Planning Committee - Fullstack application created with a group which allows a user to save information about a get together they want to share with others. Saves and maps out the address of the event, has a message board to save comments, and saves contact information of all guests attending.

Uses MySQL as the database, Google Maps API, and AJAX calls another API for quotes in the header.

Deployment: https://partyplanningcommittee.herokuapp.com/
https://partyplanningcommittee.herokuapp.com/
https://partyplanningcommittee.herokuapp.com/

About Your Birthday - Application where a user can input the date of their birthday and receive a lot of interesting information in return. The app will give them the top movie of their birth year, their zodiac sign and horoscope, what space looked like on their birthday last year using NASA photos and video, interesting facts about the specific numbers involved in their birthday, and which celebrities they share their birthday with.

This app uses many API calls to pull the information needed

Deployment: https://keithbillings.github.io/About-Your-Birthday/
https://github.com/KeithBillings/About-Your-Birthday/